Richard Hladík

Zürich, Switzerland $+41\ 76\ 229\ 45\ 30$

(a) rhladik@student.ethz.ch

rihl.uralyx.cz

A first-year student of the Computer science MSc programme at ETH Zürich, currently exploring ways of maximising my impact. I love pushing the boundaries of human knowledge and creating what hasn't been created before, especially in a group of similarly enthusiastic people. Research interests: algorithms, data structures, combinatorial optimization and flow networks.

Education

Sept. 2021-Now MSc in Computer science

(expected graduation: June 2023)

ETH Zürich

Sept. 2017-June 2021 Bc. in Computer science

Charles University, Faculty of Mathematics and Physics, Prague perfect grades (GPA of 1.00) throughout the studies and 224 ECTS credits

May 2017 upper secondary education

Grammar School and Commercial Academy Mariánské Lázně

Achievements & Awards

2021 ETH-D scholarship for excellent Master's students

2018 ACM-ICPC World Finals[†] – 56th place

2017 International Olympiad in Informatics – Silver medal (69th place)

2016 ACM-ICPC Central European Regional Contest[†] – 12th place (unofficial participation)

2016 International Olympiad in Informatics – Bronze medal (154th place)

Research Experience

MAR. 2020-Jun. 2021 Computer Science Institute, Charles University, Prague. Research in network flows

and convex optimisation, supervised by Martin Koutecký. A part of a Student Faculty Grant and a superset of my bachelor's thesis. We have proposed two new combinatorial algorithms for the multicommodity flow (MCF) problem, and tied their time complexity

to combinatorial properties of the MCF polyhedron. Journal article(s) in progress.

June 2018-Dec. 2020 Industrial Informatics Research Center, Czech Technical University, Prague. Part-time research in scheduling and optimisation, supervised by Anna Minaeva. Proved NPhardness of a certain periodic scheduling problem, developed and tested several new heuristics for it, proposed a new method for generating problem instances. Primary

author of the resulting conference paper.

Publications

[1] Richard Hladík, Anna Minaeva, and Zdeněk Hanzálek. On the complexity of a periodic scheduling problem with precedence relations. In International Conference on Combinatorial Optimization and Applications, page 107-124. Springer, 2020.

Projects

Outotune (2020-Now) - a harmoniser with VST3, LV2 and JACK support written in C++. Lets you sing chords in real time using a MIDI keyboard and your voice, by analysing it and resynthesising it at different pitches.

Programming languages & technologies

Professionally worked with C++ and Python, also fluent in C, sh and T_FX. Worked with C# and Haskell at some point. Experience with Git, NumPy, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, among others. Long-time Linux user with server administration experience.

Other

Languages: Czech (native), English (C2 – CAE Grade A), German (B2), French (basics) Authorisations: I'm a holder of an EU passport and an EU driver's licence of class B.

In my free time, I help to organise seminars, competitions and educational camps for talented highschoolers:

2018-Now Czech Olympiad in Informatics, Czech IOI Selection Camp – a series of off- and on-site competitions for Czech highschoolers that selects the Czech team for the International Olympiad in Informatics.

2017–2020 KSP – an algorithmisation correspondence seminar for Czech highschoolers; had one of leading roles in 2018–2019, managing 10–20 people and having responsibility for the seminar's main category.

Czech-Polish-Slovak Preparation Camp – a series of on-site competitions for high school students 2018-2019 advancing to the International Olympiad in Informatics.

[†] a team competition; with my friends Václav Volhejn and Filip Bialas